{"relation_id":"P1001","preferred_head_types":["ORG","MISC"],"preferred_tail_types":["LOC"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":[],"constraint_notes":"Typically an institution or other item applying to a territorial jurisdiction; the head domain is broad, so these types are soft.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P102","preferred_head_types":["PER"],"preferred_tail_types":["ORG"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":[],"constraint_notes":"A person is affiliated with a political-party organization; no broader membership relation is treated as equivalent.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P1056","preferred_head_types":["ORG","LOC","MISC"],"preferred_tail_types":["MISC"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":["P176"],"confusion_relation_ids":[],"constraint_notes":"An organization, industry, facility, or process (typically ORG/LOC/MISC) points to a product, material, service, or other output (MISC). P176 is only a directional counterpart: it is limited to a product's main or final manufacturer, whereas P1056 also covers materials, services, and processes.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P108","preferred_head_types":["PER"],"preferred_tail_types":["PER","ORG"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":["P69"],"constraint_notes":"A person points to an employer; educational affiliation has a similar PER-to-ORG signature but a different role.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P112","preferred_head_types":["ORG","LOC","MISC"],"preferred_tail_types":["PER","ORG"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":["P127","P488"],"constraint_notes":"Founded entity points to founder; ownership and organizational leadership can share arguments but do not assert founding.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P118","preferred_head_types":["PER","ORG","MISC"],"preferred_tail_types":["ORG","MISC"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":["P54"],"constraint_notes":"Player, team, or event points to a league or competition; sports-team membership is a distinct affiliation.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P1198","preferred_head_types":["LOC","MISC"],"preferred_tail_types":["NUM"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":[],"constraint_notes":"A territory or population points to a numeric unemployment rate; population typing is not uniquely determined.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P123","preferred_head_types":["MISC"],"preferred_tail_types":["PER","ORG"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":["P264","P272","P449"],"constraint_notes":"A work points to its publisher; record label, production company, and original broadcaster are distinct dissemination or production roles.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P127","preferred_head_types":[],"preferred_tail_types":["PER","ORG"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":["P112","P137"],"constraint_notes":"Owned subjects span many types, so the head preference is empty; founder and operator roles do not imply ownership.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P131","preferred_head_types":["LOC"],"preferred_tail_types":["LOC"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":["P150"],"confusion_relation_ids":["P276","P706"],"constraint_notes":"A geographic item (typically LOC) points to its administrative container (LOC). P150 is only a directional counterpart because it is limited to direct administrative subdivisions; P276 and P706 instead express non-administrative or physical-feature location.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P1336","preferred_head_types":["LOC"],"preferred_tail_types":["LOC"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":[],"constraint_notes":"Claimed territory points to the polity or administrative division making the claim; this is not ordinary containment or ownership.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P1344","preferred_head_types":["PER","ORG","MISC"],"preferred_tail_types":["MISC"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":["P710"],"confusion_relation_ids":[],"constraint_notes":"A person, organization, group-like item, or creative work (PER/ORG/MISC) points to an event (MISC) in which it participated. P710 is only a directional counterpart because its participant domain and team guidance are not coextensive.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P136","preferred_head_types":["PER","ORG","MISC"],"preferred_tail_types":["MISC"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":[],"constraint_notes":"A creative work or artist points to a genre or artistic field; artist and genre coarse types remain broad.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P1365","preferred_head_types":["PER","ORG","LOC","MISC"],"preferred_tail_types":["PER","ORG","LOC","MISC"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":["P1366"],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":["P155"],"constraint_notes":"A replacing person, organization, state, office, or item (typically PER/ORG/LOC/MISC) points to what it replaces of similar type. P1366 is its exact inverse; P155 is fixed-direction confusion because ordinary sequence following need not involve replacement.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P1366","preferred_head_types":["PER","ORG","LOC","MISC"],"preferred_tail_types":["PER","ORG","LOC","MISC"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":["P1365"],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":["P156"],"constraint_notes":"A replaced person, organization, state, office, or item (typically PER/ORG/LOC/MISC) points to its replacement of similar type. P1365 is its exact inverse; P156 is fixed-direction confusion because ordinary continuation need not involve replacement.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P137","preferred_head_types":["LOC","MISC"],"preferred_tail_types":["PER","ORG","MISC"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":["P127"],"constraint_notes":"Equipment, a facility, or a service (typically LOC/MISC) points to its operator (PER/ORG/MISC, including a profession or other entity). P127 is fixed-direction confusion because operation does not imply ownership; all types are soft.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P1376","preferred_head_types":["LOC"],"preferred_tail_types":["LOC"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":["P36"],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":[],"constraint_notes":"A municipality (typically LOC) points to the administrative division (LOC) for which it is the governmental seat; P36 is the exact inverse in that normal scope. The project wording broadens the head to a settlement, so that extension still needs review.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P140","preferred_head_types":["PER","ORG","LOC"],"preferred_tail_types":["MISC"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":["P172"],"constraint_notes":"A person, organization, or religious building points to a religion or worldview; ethnicity is a distinct identity attribute.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P1412","preferred_head_types":["PER","MISC"],"preferred_tail_types":["MISC"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":[],"constraint_notes":"A person or people points to a language spoken, written, or signed; collective-people typing is ambiguous.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P1441","preferred_head_types":["PER","ORG","LOC","MISC"],"preferred_tail_types":["MISC"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":["P674"],"confusion_relation_ids":[],"constraint_notes":"A fictional or fictionalized person, organization, place, or other entity (PER/ORG/LOC/MISC) points to its narrative work (MISC). P674 is only a directional counterpart because it covers the narrower character-in-work case.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P150","preferred_head_types":["LOC"],"preferred_tail_types":["LOC"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":["P131"],"confusion_relation_ids":[],"constraint_notes":"An administrative territory (LOC) points to a direct administrative subdivision (LOC). P131 is only a directional counterpart because P131 broadly locates items within administrative territory and is not restricted to direct subdivisions.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P155","preferred_head_types":[],"preferred_tail_types":[],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":["P156"],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":["P1365","P807"],"constraint_notes":"A later series item points to its immediate predecessor, with both type preferences left open. P156 is its exact inverse; P1365 and P807 are fixed-direction confusions that respectively require replacement or separation.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P156","preferred_head_types":[],"preferred_tail_types":[],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":["P155"],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":["P1366"],"constraint_notes":"An earlier series item points to its immediate successor, with both type preferences left open. P155 is its exact inverse; P1366 is fixed-direction confusion because replacement is stronger than sequence continuation.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P159","preferred_head_types":["ORG"],"preferred_tail_types":["LOC"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":["P740","P937"],"constraint_notes":"An organization (ORG) points to its headquarters city or town (LOC); P740 and P937 are fixed-direction confusions for formation and work locations. The project phrase 'other place' is broader than the Wikidata city-or-town scope.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P161","preferred_head_types":["MISC"],"preferred_tail_types":["PER"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":[],"constraint_notes":"A production (typically MISC) points to an actor (PER). The Wikidata scope excludes voice-only roles and directs non-fiction participation elsewhere, while the project wording broadens this to performers and other productions.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P162","preferred_head_types":["MISC"],"preferred_tail_types":["PER"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":["P57"],"constraint_notes":"Creative work points to its producer; director is a distinct production role with the same common argument signature.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P166","preferred_head_types":["PER","ORG","MISC"],"preferred_tail_types":["MISC"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":[],"constraint_notes":"A person, organization, or work points to an award or recognition it received.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P17","preferred_head_types":[],"preferred_tail_types":["LOC"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":[],"constraint_notes":"A non-human subject points to its sovereign country; the broad subject domain makes a head-type preference unreliable.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P170","preferred_head_types":["MISC"],"preferred_tail_types":["PER","ORG"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":["P800"],"confusion_relation_ids":[],"constraint_notes":"A creative work or other object (typically MISC) points to its creator (PER/ORG) where no more specific property applies. P800 is only a directional counterpart because it reverses the narrower notable-work subset.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P171","preferred_head_types":["MISC"],"preferred_tail_types":["MISC"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":["P279"],"constraint_notes":"Taxon points to its closest parent taxon; general subclassing has a similar hierarchy shape but different semantics.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P172","preferred_head_types":["PER"],"preferred_tail_types":["MISC"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":["P140"],"constraint_notes":"A person points to an explicitly established ethnic group; religion or worldview is a distinct identity attribute.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P175","preferred_head_types":["MISC"],"preferred_tail_types":["PER","ORG"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":["P676","P86"],"constraint_notes":"Role or musical work points to a performer; lyricist and composer may share people but assert different creative roles.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P176","preferred_head_types":["MISC"],"preferred_tail_types":["PER","ORG"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":["P1056"],"confusion_relation_ids":["P178"],"constraint_notes":"A product or physical item (MISC) points to its main or final manufacturer (PER/ORG). P1056 is only a directional counterpart because it also covers broader producers, materials, services, and processes; P178 is fixed-direction confusion for development.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P178","preferred_head_types":["MISC"],"preferred_tail_types":["PER","ORG"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":["P176"],"constraint_notes":"Software, game, product, or work points to its developer; manufacturer is a distinct role, while generic creator may legitimately overlap.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P179","preferred_head_types":["MISC"],"preferred_tail_types":["MISC"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":[],"constraint_notes":"An item points to the series containing it; generic part-of is broader and is not declared equivalent.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P19","preferred_head_types":["PER","MISC"],"preferred_tail_types":["LOC"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":["P20","P27","P551"],"constraint_notes":"Person, animal, or fictional character points to birth location; death, citizenship, and residence share coarse types but differ semantically.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P190","preferred_head_types":["LOC"],"preferred_tail_types":["LOC"],"directionality":"symmetric","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":[],"constraint_notes":"Two local administrative bodies have a reciprocal twinning partnership; swapping head and tail preserves meaning.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P194","preferred_head_types":["LOC"],"preferred_tail_types":["ORG"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":[],"constraint_notes":"A political territory points to its legislative body; governmental-subject coarse typing may require review.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P20","preferred_head_types":["PER","MISC"],"preferred_tail_types":["LOC"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":["P19","P27","P551"],"constraint_notes":"Person, animal, or fictional character points to death location; birth, citizenship, and residence share coarse types but differ semantically.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P205","preferred_head_types":["LOC"],"preferred_tail_types":["LOC"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":[],"constraint_notes":"Body of water points to a country in its drainage or border basin; both arguments are geographic but roles are directional.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P206","preferred_head_types":["LOC"],"preferred_tail_types":["LOC"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":["P403","P706"],"constraint_notes":"Geographic entity points to an adjacent or containing body of water; watercourse mouth and physical-feature location are distinct.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P22","preferred_head_types":["PER"],"preferred_tail_types":["PER"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":["P40"],"confusion_relation_ids":["P25"],"constraint_notes":"A child (PER) points to the child's father (PER). P40 is a directional counterpart, not an exact inverse, because the reversed child relation does not itself assert a male parent; P25 remains fixed-direction confusion for mother.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P241","preferred_head_types":["PER","ORG","MISC"],"preferred_tail_types":["ORG"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":[],"constraint_notes":"A person, military unit, organization, award, or office (typically PER/ORG/MISC) points to its armed-service branch (ORG). The project description omits awards and offices, so the broader Wikidata head scope is retained as soft typing.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P25","preferred_head_types":["PER"],"preferred_tail_types":["PER"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":["P40"],"confusion_relation_ids":["P22"],"constraint_notes":"A child (PER) points to the child's mother (PER). P40 is a directional counterpart, not an exact inverse, because the reversed child relation does not itself assert a female parent; P22 remains fixed-direction confusion for father.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P26","preferred_head_types":["PER"],"preferred_tail_types":["PER"],"directionality":"symmetric","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":["P3373"],"constraint_notes":"Spouse relation is unchanged by argument exchange; sibling has the same symmetric PER-PER shape but a different kinship meaning.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P264","preferred_head_types":["MISC"],"preferred_tail_types":["ORG","MISC"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":["P123","P272"],"constraint_notes":"Music recording points to a record-label brand; publisher and production company are distinct commercial roles.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P27","preferred_head_types":["PER"],"preferred_tail_types":["LOC"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":["P19","P20","P551"],"constraint_notes":"Person points to country of citizenship; birth, death, and residence locations have the same coarse signature but different claims.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P272","preferred_head_types":["MISC"],"preferred_tail_types":["ORG"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":["P123","P264","P449"],"constraint_notes":"A film, audio, or performing-arts work (MISC) points to its production company (ORG); publisher, label, and broadcaster are fixed-direction confusions. The project wording additionally covers television, games, and other creative works, a broader scope needing review.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P276","preferred_head_types":["LOC","MISC"],"preferred_tail_types":["LOC"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":["P131"],"constraint_notes":"An object, structure, or event (typically LOC/MISC) points to its physical location (LOC). P131 is fixed-direction confusion for administrative containment; the type preferences are soft because the head domain is broad.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P279","preferred_head_types":["MISC"],"preferred_tail_types":["MISC"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":["P31","P171"],"constraint_notes":"Narrower class points to broader class; instance-of and taxonomic parent relations have similar hierarchy shapes but different semantics.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P30","preferred_head_types":["LOC"],"preferred_tail_types":["LOC"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":[],"constraint_notes":"Geographic entity points to its containing continent.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P31","preferred_head_types":[],"preferred_tail_types":["MISC"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":["P279"],"constraint_notes":"Any entity may point to its class, so the head preference is empty; subclass-of instead relates two classes.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P3373","preferred_head_types":["PER"],"preferred_tail_types":["PER"],"directionality":"symmetric","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":["P26"],"constraint_notes":"Sibling relation is unchanged by argument exchange; spouse has the same symmetric PER-PER shape but a different kinship meaning.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P35","preferred_head_types":["LOC"],"preferred_tail_types":["PER"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":["P6"],"constraint_notes":"Country or state points to its formal head of state; head of government is a distinct executive role.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P355","preferred_head_types":["ORG"],"preferred_tail_types":["ORG"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":["P749"],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":[],"constraint_notes":"A parent organization or unit (ORG) points to its child organization or unit (ORG). P749 is its exact inverse under the Wikidata organizational-parent meaning.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P36","preferred_head_types":["LOC"],"preferred_tail_types":["LOC"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":["P1376"],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":[],"constraint_notes":"An administrative territory (LOC) points to its governmental-seat city or place (LOC). P1376 is the exact inverse in the normal municipality-seat scope; broader readings of settlement or place need review.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P361","preferred_head_types":[],"preferred_tail_types":[],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":["P527"],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":[],"constraint_notes":"A component points to the whole of which it is part, with both coarse type preferences left open. P527 is its exact inverse across the same generic part-whole scope.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P364","preferred_head_types":["MISC"],"preferred_tail_types":["MISC"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":[],"constraint_notes":"Film or performance work points to its original language; language is represented conservatively as MISC.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P37","preferred_head_types":["ORG","LOC"],"preferred_tail_types":["MISC"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":[],"constraint_notes":"Country, region, organization, or other item points to an officially designated language; subject typing is broad.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P39","preferred_head_types":["PER"],"preferred_tail_types":["MISC"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":[],"constraint_notes":"Person points to a held office, role, or position; this is not generic organization membership.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P40","preferred_head_types":["PER"],"preferred_tail_types":["PER"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":["P22","P25"],"confusion_relation_ids":[],"constraint_notes":"A parent (PER) points to a child (PER). P22 and P25 are directional counterparts, not exact inverses, because they additionally assert that the reversed parent is respectively male or female; they are not fixed-direction confusions.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P400","preferred_head_types":["MISC"],"preferred_tail_types":["MISC"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":[],"constraint_notes":"Work or software product points to a development or release platform.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P403","preferred_head_types":["LOC"],"preferred_tail_types":["LOC"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":["P206"],"constraint_notes":"Watercourse points to the body of water into which it drains; general adjacency to water is a different relation.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P449","preferred_head_types":["MISC"],"preferred_tail_types":["ORG","MISC"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":["P123","P272"],"constraint_notes":"A radio or television program (MISC) points to its original network or service (typically ORG/MISC). P123 and P272 are fixed-direction confusions for publisher and production company; service need not be an organization.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P463","preferred_head_types":["PER","ORG"],"preferred_tail_types":["ORG"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":[],"constraint_notes":"Person or organization points to an organization, group, or body of which it is a member; specialized membership predicates remain distinct.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P488","preferred_head_types":["ORG"],"preferred_tail_types":["PER"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":["P112"],"constraint_notes":"Organization or body points to its chairperson; organizational leadership does not imply founding.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P495","preferred_head_types":["MISC"],"preferred_tail_types":["LOC"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":[],"constraint_notes":"Work, product, or item points to its country of origin; the broad head domain is represented as MISC.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P50","preferred_head_types":["MISC"],"preferred_tail_types":["PER"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":["P58","P676"],"constraint_notes":"Written work points to its author; screenplay and lyric writing are narrower roles with similar argument signatures.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P527","preferred_head_types":[],"preferred_tail_types":[],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":["P361"],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":[],"constraint_notes":"A whole points to one of its components, with both coarse type preferences left open. P361 is its exact inverse across the same generic part-whole scope.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P54","preferred_head_types":["PER"],"preferred_tail_types":["ORG"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":["P118"],"constraint_notes":"Athlete or player points to a sports team; league or competition participation is a distinct affiliation.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P551","preferred_head_types":["PER"],"preferred_tail_types":["LOC"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":["P19","P20","P27","P937"],"constraint_notes":"Person points to residence; birth, death, citizenship, and work locations share coarse types but assert different roles.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P569","preferred_head_types":["PER"],"preferred_tail_types":["TIME"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":["P570"],"constraint_notes":"Person points to birth date or time; death date has the same PER-to-TIME signature but opposite lifecycle meaning.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P57","preferred_head_types":["MISC"],"preferred_tail_types":["PER"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":["P58","P162"],"constraint_notes":"Creative work points to director; screenwriter and producer are distinct production roles with similar arguments.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P570","preferred_head_types":["PER"],"preferred_tail_types":["TIME"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":["P569"],"constraint_notes":"Person points to death date or time; birth date has the same PER-to-TIME signature but opposite lifecycle meaning.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P571","preferred_head_types":[],"preferred_tail_types":["TIME"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":["P576","P577","P580"],"constraint_notes":"Broad entity points to inception time; dissolution, publication, and generic start times are related temporal predicates but not equivalent.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P576","preferred_head_types":["ORG","LOC"],"preferred_tail_types":["TIME"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":["P571","P582"],"constraint_notes":"An organization or building (typically ORG/LOC) points to the time it ceased to exist (TIME); inception and generic end time are fixed-direction confusions. The project phrase 'other entity' is broader than the Wikidata scope and needs review.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P577","preferred_head_types":["MISC"],"preferred_tail_types":["TIME"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":["P571","P585"],"constraint_notes":"Work or product points to first publication or release time; inception and generic point-in-time predicates are distinct.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P58","preferred_head_types":["MISC"],"preferred_tail_types":["PER"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":["P50","P57"],"constraint_notes":"Work points to screenplay or script writer; generic author and director are distinct creative roles.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P580","preferred_head_types":[],"preferred_tail_types":["TIME"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":["P571","P582","P585"],"constraint_notes":"Broad entity, event, role, or statement points to start time; inception, end time, and point in time require distinct temporal readings.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P582","preferred_head_types":[],"preferred_tail_types":["TIME"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":["P576","P580","P585"],"constraint_notes":"Broad entity, event, role, or statement points to end time; dissolution, start time, and point in time are distinct temporal readings.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P585","preferred_head_types":[],"preferred_tail_types":["TIME"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":["P577","P580","P582"],"constraint_notes":"Event, entity, or statement points to a time at which it occurred or held; publication, start, and end predicates are more specific.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P6","preferred_head_types":["ORG","LOC"],"preferred_tail_types":["PER"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":["P35"],"constraint_notes":"A governmental territory or body (typically LOC/ORG) points to its executive leader (PER). P35 is fixed-direction confusion for the distinct head-of-state role; these coarse types are soft.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P607","preferred_head_types":["PER","ORG","MISC"],"preferred_tail_types":["MISC"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":[],"constraint_notes":"A person or other participating item (typically PER/ORG/MISC) points to a military conflict (MISC). Generic event participation is broader and is not added as fixed-direction confusion.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P674","preferred_head_types":["MISC"],"preferred_tail_types":["PER","MISC"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":["P1441"],"confusion_relation_ids":[],"constraint_notes":"A work (MISC) points to a character appearing in it (typically PER/MISC). P1441 is only a directional counterpart because its reversed scope also covers fictionalized places and other entities; the project's 'fictional character' wording is narrower than the source label.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P676","preferred_head_types":["MISC"],"preferred_tail_types":["PER"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":["P50","P175","P86"],"constraint_notes":"Song or musical work points to lyricist; author, performer, and composer roles can share people but remain distinct.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P69","preferred_head_types":["PER"],"preferred_tail_types":["ORG"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":["P108"],"constraint_notes":"Person points to an attended educational institution; employer has the same common type signature but a different affiliation.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P706","preferred_head_types":["LOC"],"preferred_tail_types":["LOC"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":["P131","P206"],"constraint_notes":"Geographic entity points to a physical feature; administrative location and body-of-water adjacency are distinct, while generic location may overlap.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P710","preferred_head_types":["MISC"],"preferred_tail_types":["PER","ORG","MISC"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":["P1344"],"confusion_relation_ids":[],"constraint_notes":"An event or process (MISC) points to an active participant (typically PER/ORG/MISC). P1344 is only a directional counterpart because its domain and P710's separate guidance for team participants make the scopes non-coextensive.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P737","preferred_head_types":["PER","MISC"],"preferred_tail_types":["PER","MISC"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":[],"constraint_notes":"A person, idea, or other entity (typically PER/MISC) points to an influencing person, idea, or entity of similarly open type. The relation is directed, not symmetric, and both type lists are only soft preferences.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P740","preferred_head_types":["ORG"],"preferred_tail_types":["LOC"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":["P159","P937"],"constraint_notes":"Group or organization points to formation location; headquarters and work locations are distinct organizational-place roles.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P749","preferred_head_types":["ORG"],"preferred_tail_types":["ORG"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":["P355"],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":[],"constraint_notes":"A child organization or unit (ORG) points to its parent organization or unit (ORG). P355 is its exact inverse under the Wikidata organizational-parent meaning; the project wording 'owns, contains, or controls' is broader and should not expand that equivalence.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P800","preferred_head_types":["PER","ORG"],"preferred_tail_types":["MISC"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":["P170"],"confusion_relation_ids":[],"constraint_notes":"A person or organization (PER/ORG) points to a notable work (MISC). P170 is only a directional counterpart because creator covers non-notable works and other created objects as well.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P807","preferred_head_types":["ORG","LOC","MISC"],"preferred_tail_types":["ORG","LOC","MISC"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":["P155"],"constraint_notes":"An entity founded or started by separation (typically ORG/LOC/MISC) points to its source entity of similarly broad type. P155 is fixed-direction confusion for ordinary series succession; the open Wikidata domain makes all listed types soft.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P840","preferred_head_types":["MISC"],"preferred_tail_types":["LOC"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":[],"constraint_notes":"Narrative work points to its fictional or narrative setting; this is not an actual physical-location assertion.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P86","preferred_head_types":["MISC"],"preferred_tail_types":["PER"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":["P175","P676"],"constraint_notes":"Musical or audiovisual work points to composer; performer and lyricist are distinct musical roles.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
{"relation_id":"P937","preferred_head_types":["PER","ORG"],"preferred_tail_types":["LOC"],"directionality":"directed","exact_inverse_relation_ids":[],"directional_counterpart_relation_ids":[],"confusion_relation_ids":["P159","P551","P740"],"constraint_notes":"Person or organization points to active work location; headquarters, residence, and formation locations are distinct roles.","source":"llm_generated_from_reviewed_relation_metadata","needs_review":false}
